<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Black Texan</title>
    <description>All things Black. All things Texan.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 11:20:26 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 11:20:26 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>No One Should Come to the Cook Out This Year</title>
        <description>Welp Texans, it’s 4th of July and we are still dealing with the spread of Covid-19, now more than ever infact. As we start our 4th of July celebrations, it is still important to heed the warnings of our state government and medical officials, those of us in the black community as we are more likely to be serriously affected by the disease due to “long-standing systemic health and social inequities”. That’s right, after years and years of inviting anyone and everyone to the “cook out”, this year it is best to keep our celebrations small.

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/no-cook-out-2020</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/no-cook-out-2020</guid>
        
        <category>covid-19</category>
        
        
        <enclosure url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/2020/cookout.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Harris County Judge Lina Hidalgo and Houston Mayor Sylvester Turner Deserve an Apology</title>
        <description>“When did we lose our respect for human life? Since when did we decide as a society that instead of saving a life … we would treat human lives as collateral damage?…”, Harris County Judge Lina Hidalgo questioned in her remarks at a press conference last week where they announced Harris County was now at its highest emergency threat level. Shortly thereafter Houston Mayor Sylvester Turner called for Houstonians to unite again and flatten the curve and progression of the virus. Watching these two officials do all they could petitioning their constituents to join together for the wellbeing of others again, I realized that we all owe these two an apology, including myself.

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/houstonians-should-apologize</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/houstonians-should-apologize</guid>
        
        <category>houston</category>
        
        <category>covid-19</category>
        
        <category>opinion</category>
        
        
        <enclosure url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/2020/apology.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Music From the Movement</title>
        <description>Artists from all over the state are creating, inspiring, and participating in protests as a reaction to the unjust killings of Black women and men across the nation. Much like the music inspired by the fight for civil rights in the sixties, the music released during this time will no doubt become linked hand in hand with memories of the movement. Check out the selections released recently below.

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/music-from-the-movement</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/music-from-the-movement</guid>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
        
        <enclosure url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/2020/aisha-burns.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Miss Juneteenth Review</title>
        <description>Those who have grown up in Texas might feel as if the characters and town featured in Miss Juneteenth were ripped right from their own lives; that’s how lived in this film feels. Released this year on Juneteenth, Fort Worth native, Channing Godfrey Peoples’ directorial debut tells the story of Turquoise, a mother striving to take care of herself and provide a future for her daughter. She sees a way to secure her daughter’s future in the annual Miss Juneteenth pageant, a pageant she herself won when she was younger. Authentic to its setting, this film moves from the charmingly greasy bar Turquoise works shifts at to the prim and proper pageant world, all in the same Texas town.

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/miss-juneteenth-review</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/miss-juneteenth-review</guid>
        
        <category>review</category>
        
        
        <enclosure url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/2020/miss-juneteenth.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Juneteenth Has Always Been a Holiday</title>
        <description>Most Black Texans and Black Americans know this to be true, Juneteenth has been celebrated for over a century now. I personally can remember my Dad explaining to me the significance and history of the date when I was child as we grilled burgers. Like many issues my Dad had to sit me down and explain, due to them not being in Texas school books, it feels as if large parts of America (especially white Americans) are just now learning of Juneteenth. How fitting that Juneteenth is not the date commemorating when slaves were freed but when they found out. While this illuminating time and movement for change in this nation is inspiring, if I had to choose between corporations sending out tweets for Juneteenth and justice for Breonna Taylor, the choice is easy. If it’s between Aunt Jemima and holding police departments accountable for the crimes they’ve committed against the citizens they are supposed to protect, I choose accountability. If it’s between every White American knowing about Juneteenth and this nation addressing it’s foundation of racism and prejudice, let’s get to fixing this nation. Blacks want both, to be clear, but in the midst of all that’s going on...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/juneteenth-already-holiday</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/juneteenth-already-holiday</guid>
        
        <category>opinion</category>
        
        
        <enclosure url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/2020/juneteenth-flag.png" type="image/jpeg" />
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Da 5 Bloods Review</title>
        <description>The new Spike Lee feature Da 5 Bloods from Netflix is a movie unlike any other released so far this year. Many films strive to either be classified as “the’’ movie for the present moment and time (Lee’s last feature BlacKkKlansman for instance) and while it doesn’t seem like Lee directed the movie with regards either way, it would be hard not to appreciate the timeliness of this movie’s release and it’s subject matter. Da 5 Bloods tells the story of four Black Vietnam War Veterans traveling back to search for the remains of their fallen comrade and buried riches. They navigate the haunting legacy of their former leader Stormin Norman (played by Black Panther star Chadwick Boseman) which weaves through the past and present day, forcing Da Bloods to relive the horrors of war. In part based on Wallace Terry’s collection of black soldiers’ accounts of the war, Da 5 Bloods is much more than a war movie. It’s mixing of genres and themes are handled masterfully by Lee who explores haunting memories of the past, the debt this country owes it’s black soldiers, and even what Black Americans owe each other. His expert direction is evident as well....</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Da-5-Bloods-Review</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Da-5-Bloods-Review</guid>
        
        <category>review</category>
        
        
        <enclosure url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/2020/da-5-bloods-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>In The Beginning...</title>
        <description>“To be Black, to be Texan, I wouldn't trade for anything in the world. I thank God for both.&quot;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/in-the-beginning</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/in-the-beginning</guid>
        
        <category>history</category>
        
        
        <enclosure url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/logo/FInal-Main-Logo-Profile.png" type="image/jpeg" />
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
