<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/author/jarrett/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2020-06-22T19:45:42-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/author/jarrett/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">The Black Texan | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>All things Black. All things Texan.</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Music From the Movement</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/music-from-the-movement" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Music From the Movement" />
      <published>2020-06-22T00:00:00-05:00</published>
      <updated>2020-06-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/music-from-the-movement</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/music-from-the-movement">&lt;p&gt;Artist from all over the state are creating, inspiring, and participating in protests as a reaction to the unjust killings of Black women and men across the nation. Much like the music inspired by the fight for civil rights in the sixties, the music released during this time will no doubt become linked hand in hand with memories of the movement. Check out the selections released recently below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Black Parade - Beyoncé&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4EHbf5QUjNE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Houston’s very own Queen Bey released her know song Black Parade in celebration of &lt;a href=&quot;https://blacktexan.com/juneteenth-already-holiday&quot;&gt;Juneteenth&lt;/a&gt; this past weekend. She says the upbeat track will benefit black own business and artists, which she &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.beyonce.com/black-parade-route/&quot;&gt;linked to on her Instagram&lt;/a&gt;. Not one to shy away from social activism and Black uplifting, Bey sings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Rubber bullets bouncing off me, made a picket sign off your picket fence, take it as a warning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An extended version of Black Parade is available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://listen.tidal.com/album/145850339&quot;&gt;Tidal.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Until We All Are Free - Aisha Burns&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&quot;border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px;&quot; src=&quot;https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=665746141/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=333333/tracklist=false/artwork=small/transparent=true/&quot; seamless=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://aishaburns.bandcamp.com/album/until-we-all-are-free-benefit-ep&quot;&gt;Until We All Are Free (Benefit EP) by Aisha Burns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Folk Singer Aisha Burns released a &lt;a href=&quot;https://aishaburns.bandcamp.com/album/until-we-all-are-free-benefit-ep&quot;&gt;new EP&lt;/a&gt; in honor of Juneteenth as well this past weekend. Proceeds from sales will go to  NAACP Legal Defense fund through Bandcamp and the Black Trans Travel Fund. The two track album by the San Antonio native spans from the constituentional commentary to modern call to action and is currently only available on Bandcamp.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Untitled (Black Is) - Sault&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/videoseries?list=OLAK5uy_mPQ1zX6FZ2noGfGMWXN9cnVkoqD18R-OM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Little is known specifically of the make up and orign of the critically acclaimed group Sault, though much &lt;a href=&quot;theguardian.com/music/2019/dec/20/sault-5-7-review-forever-living-originals&quot;&gt;speculated&lt;/a&gt;. They soar past their already high heights on their latest release which is deeply rooted in the present moment of Black experience. Through addictive rythyms and beautiful melodies, Sault uplift and narrate the beauty, joys, and challneges of Blackness.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;I Can't Breathe - H.E.R.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IRZWiqBHYaY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, last week dropped the audio for her new somber and thought song “I Can’t Breathe”. With a extensive, personal spoken word section. H.E.R. makes it plain her view on the current tragedies of this world.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Jarrett Johnson</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="music" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Artist from all over the state are creating, inspiring, and participating in protests as a reaction to the unjust killings of Black women and men across the nation. Much like the music inspired by the fight for civil rights in the sixties, the music released during this time will no doubt become linked hand in hand with memories of the movement. Check out the selections released recently below.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Juneteenth Has Always Been a Holiday</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/juneteenth-already-holiday" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Juneteenth Has Always Been a Holiday" />
      <published>2020-06-19T00:00:00-05:00</published>
      <updated>2020-06-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/juneteenth-already-holiday</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/juneteenth-already-holiday">&lt;p&gt;Most Black Texans and Black Americans know this to be true, Juneteenth has been celebrated for over a century now. I personally can remember my Dad explaining to me the significance and history of the date when I was child as we grilled burgers. Like many issues my Dad had to sit me down and explain, due to them &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.yahoo.com/did-learn-juneteenth-school-many-210400496.html&quot;&gt;not being in Texas school books&lt;/a&gt;, it feels as if large parts of America (especially white Americans) are just now learning of Juneteenth. &lt;!--more--&gt; How fitting that Juneteenth is not the date commemorating when slaves were freed but when they &lt;em&gt;found out&lt;/em&gt;. While this illuminating time and movement for change in this nation is inspiring, if I had to choose between corporations sending out tweets for Juneteenth and justice for Breonna Taylor, the choice is easy. If it’s between &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2020/06/19/business/racist-brands-aunt-jemima-chiquita/index.html&quot;&gt;Aunt Jemima&lt;/a&gt; and holding police departments accountable for the crimes they’ve committed against the citizens they are supposed to protect, I choose accountability. If it’s between every White American knowing about Juneteenth and this nation addressing it’s foundation of racism and prejudice, let’s get to fixing this nation. Blacks want both, to be clear, but in the midst of all that’s going on in America it’s important not to lose focus. Rev. Dr. William J. Barber II said it best:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet tw-align-center &quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Some are calling for Juneteenth to be a national holiday. How about we go further &amp;amp; pass healthcare &amp;amp; living wages for all, a fully restored Voting Rights Act &amp;amp; reparations, etc. Please don’t just ask for a holiday. Let’s make it a holy day of repentance &amp;amp; reconstruction.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rev. Dr. William J. Barber II (@RevDrBarber) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RevDrBarber/status/1273993146960052225?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 19, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I commend all who for whatever reason are just now learning about Juneteeth and other parts of the Black experience and are doing their best to listen and educate themselves. There is plenty &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/article/juneteenth-day-celebration.html&quot;&gt;written about the holiday&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pbs.org/wnet/african-americans-many-rivers-to-cross/history/what-is-juneteenth/&quot;&gt;it’s history.&lt;/a&gt; Hopefully lessons we collectively take from Juneteenth lead us to substantive change for Black communities and not just a day off work and sales on bedding and furniture like other holidays. Without changes to corporate hiring policies, inclusion in leadership positions and bias training, the various corporate acknowledgements  ring hollow. If the Breonna Taylor’s murderers are allowed to continue on with their lives without being tried for their crimes, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wlky.com/article/gov-beshear-signs-proclamation-making-friday-juneteenth-national-freedom-day/32910987&quot;&gt;proclamations from the governor&lt;/a&gt; are just words. This moment in America started not to get a day off from work, though that is a great result, but to seek justice for those wronged by it’s system of oppression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;alignleft&quot;&gt;“Hopefully lessons we collectively take from Juneteenth lead us to substantive change for Black communities and not just a day off work and sales on bedding and furniture like other holidays.&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, Juneteenth will continue to be a holiday for Black Texans and Americans whether the president acknowledges it all, just like it’s always been. Like New Year’s watch meetings, we will continue to commemorate and celebrate the sacrifices of those who came before us, that’s who we are. However, If we want to be like our forerunners who fought for their and our freedom, let’s be mindful not to just fight for holidays though and instead work for positive change and making this nation a better place for those that follow us.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Jarrett Johnson</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="opinion" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Most Black Texans and Black Americans know this to be true, Juneteenth has been celebrated for over a century now. I personally can remember my Dad explaining to me the significance and history of the date when I was child as we grilled burgers. Like many issues my Dad had to sit me down and explain, due to them not being in Texas school books, it feels as if large parts of America (especially white Americans) are just now learning of Juneteenth. How fitting that Juneteenth is not the date commemorating when slaves were freed but when they found out. While this illuminating time and movement for change in this nation is inspiring, if I had to choose between corporations sending out tweets for Juneteenth and justice for Breonna Taylor, the choice is easy. If it’s between Aunt Jemima and holding police departments accountable for the crimes they’ve committed against the citizens they are supposed to protect, I choose accountability. If it’s between every White American knowing about Juneteenth and this nation addressing it’s foundation of racism and prejudice, let’s get to fixing this nation. Blacks want both, to be clear, but in the midst of all that’s going on in America it’s important not to lose focus. Rev. Dr. William J. Barber II said it best:</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Miss Juneteenth Review</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/miss-juneteenth-review" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Miss Juneteenth Review" />
      <published>2020-06-19T00:00:00-05:00</published>
      <updated>2020-06-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/miss-juneteenth-review</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/miss-juneteenth-review">&lt;p&gt;Those who have grown up in Texas might feel as if the characters and town featured in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/video/detail/amzn1.dv.gti.86b91995-f66a-7401-2f12-65edff41ca55&quot;&gt;Miss Juneteenth&lt;/a&gt; were ripped right from their own lives; that’s how lived in this film feels. Released this year on &lt;a href=&quot;https://blacktexan.com/juneteenth-already-holiday&quot;&gt;Juneteenth&lt;/a&gt;, Fort Worth native, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/name/nm1474677/&quot;&gt;Channing Godfrey Peoples’&lt;/a&gt; directorial debut tells the story of Turquoise, a mother striving to take care of herself and provide a future for her daughter. She sees a way to secure her daughter’s future in the annual Miss Juneteenth pageant, a pageant she herself won when she was younger. Authentic to its setting, this film moves from the charmingly greasy bar Turquoise works shifts at to the prim and proper pageant world, all in the same Texas town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2020/miss-juneteenth-1.jpg#right&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Nicole Beharie and Alexis Chikaze in Miss Juneteenth&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like pageant movies before it, the plot centers around an unlikely contestant striving to win, however, Miss Juneteenth’s contestant is Turquoise’s daughter, Kai, who is more reluctant than she is unlikely. Nicole Beharie is endearing in her role as Turquoise who has to overcome not just the present day obstacles in front of her family but echoes from her past. Side note: This world needs more Nicole Beharie movies. Adding to the authenticity of the movie is the casting of charismatic Houston, Texas native Kendrick Sampson who you might recognize from his role as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vulture.com/article/kendrick-sampson-interview-insecure-miss-juneteenth-blm-protests.html&quot;&gt;Nathan in the hit HBO show Insecure.&lt;/a&gt; His character brings forward issues both Turquoise and Kai must reckon with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What struck me the most, as I’ve said before, is how familiar the movie felt. From the side characters, to the people walking around town on the periphery of the screen. While I have never been in a pageant myself nor have I lived in Fort Worth, I have met many of the characters depicted here. For instance, at one point in the movie Turquoise and Kai visit a local Blcak church and we see the service going on. I was transported right into this scene; every hat was in place, every “hallelujah” in tune. I would like to know how many in this cast were paid actors as at times it seemed as if Peoples dropped cameras and her actors into a real town and said “action”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2020/miss-juneteenth-2.jpg#wide&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From its depiction of the mother-daughter relationship to the sincerity of the performance by Nicole Beharie you will be moved by this film. Miss Juneteenth is a slice of Texan life depicted on the big screen, or to be correct, your streaming platform. Whether you check it out this weekend of its release or two years later when you find out about it, it is definitely worth the watch.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Jarrett Johnson</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="review" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Those who have grown up in Texas might feel as if the characters and town featured in Miss Juneteenth were ripped right from their own lives; that’s how lived in this film feels. Released this year on Juneteenth, Fort Worth native, Channing Godfrey Peoples’ directorial debut tells the story of Turquoise, a mother striving to take care of herself and provide a future for her daughter. She sees a way to secure her daughter’s future in the annual Miss Juneteenth pageant, a pageant she herself won when she was younger. Authentic to its setting, this film moves from the charmingly greasy bar Turquoise works shifts at to the prim and proper pageant world, all in the same Texas town.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Da 5 Bloods Review</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/Da-5-Bloods-Review" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Da 5 Bloods Review" />
      <published>2020-06-13T00:00:00-05:00</published>
      <updated>2020-06-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/Da-5-Bloods-Review</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Da-5-Bloods-Review">&lt;p&gt;The new Spike Lee feature &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflix.com/title/81045635&quot;&gt;Da 5 Bloods&lt;/a&gt; from Netflix is a movie unlike any other released so far this year. &lt;!--more--&gt; Many films strive to either be classified as “the’’ movie for the present moment and time (Lee’s last feature BlacKkKlansman for instance) and while it doesn’t seem like Lee directed the movie with regards either way, it would be hard not to appreciate the timeliness of this movie’s release and it’s subject matter. Da 5 Bloods tells the story of four Black Vietnam War Veterans traveling back to search for the remains of their fallen comrade and buried riches. They navigate the haunting legacy of their former leader Stormin Norman (played by Black Panther star Chadwick Boseman) which weaves through the past and present day, forcing Da Bloods to relive the horrors of war.  In part based on Wallace Terry’s collection of black soldiers’ accounts of the war, Da 5 Bloods is much more than a war movie. It’s mixing of genres and themes are handled masterfully by Lee who explores haunting memories of the past, the debt this country owes it’s black soldiers, and even what Black Americans owe each other. His expert direction is evident as well. The setting and genre of a Vietnam War film allowed him to draw from inspiration ranging from the obvious Apocalypse Now to documentary footage of the true atrocities of the war. Tying this all together to make an entertaining film is an achievement and thanks in large part to the landmark performances of the cast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2020/da-5-bloods-2.jpg#left&quot; alt=&quot;Delroy Lindo and Jonathon Majors from Da 5 Bloods&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The up and coming Dallas native Jonathan Majors shone brightly in films such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.metacritic.com/movie/hostiles&quot;&gt;Hostiles&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://a24films.com/films/the-last-black-man-in-san-francisco&quot;&gt;The Last Black Man in San Francisco&lt;/a&gt; and he continues this run of form with his performance as David, the son of one the titular Bloods. The youthfulness of this character plays as a contrast to the senior citizen rest of the main cast. Upon first seeing Da Bloods on screen their chemistry is palpable; it’s easy to believe these now aged men have been friends for decades. Isiah Whitlock Jr., Norm Lewis, Clarke Lewis, and Delroy Lindo are Da Bloods in present day, each processing the consequences of the war and their lives afterwards in their own way. While largely a fictional story, the film is rooted in the experience of black veterans. Abstract ideas from the role of Black Americans in the history of the American military, to the opioid crisis, to how best to respond to injustice and tragedy are illustrated through conversations between Da Bloods and various characters they encounter along the way. These conversations resemble the real ones being had by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gov.texas.gov/uploads/files/organization/twic/Veterans_in_Texas_2016_Update.pdf&quot;&gt;13% of Black Texans&lt;/a&gt;, though heighted by the situation Da Bloods find themselves in. Lee clearly has a lot to say on these things and doesn’t pull any punches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2020/da-5-bloods-3.jpg#wide&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These punches hit the hardest from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/name/nm0005148/&quot;&gt;Delroy Lindo’s&lt;/a&gt; character, Paul. It’s hard not to want to join in the online campaign already forming for a Lindo Oscar nomination. His is the Blood most plagued by the death of their former leader and the complicated relationship he has with his family drives some of the most emotional parts of the movie. A role that could have easily become a caricature was handled with nuance and passion. Ultimately, the same is true for the film at large. Da 5 Bloods is deservedly the best movie of the year so far and more than that, deserves a spot in the upper echelon of the Spike Lee.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Jarrett Johnson</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="review" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">The new Spike Lee feature Da 5 Bloods from Netflix is a movie unlike any other released so far this year. Many films strive to either be classified as “the’’ movie for the present moment and time (Lee’s last feature BlacKkKlansman for instance) and while it doesn’t seem like Lee directed the movie with regards either way, it would be hard not to appreciate the timeliness of this movie’s release and it’s subject matter. Da 5 Bloods tells the story of four Black Vietnam War Veterans traveling back to search for the remains of their fallen comrade and buried riches. They navigate the haunting legacy of their former leader Stormin Norman (played by Black Panther star Chadwick Boseman) which weaves through the past and present day, forcing Da Bloods to relive the horrors of war. In part based on Wallace Terry’s collection of black soldiers’ accounts of the war, Da 5 Bloods is much more than a war movie. It’s mixing of genres and themes are handled masterfully by Lee who explores haunting memories of the past, the debt this country owes it’s black soldiers, and even what Black Americans owe each other. His expert direction is evident as well. The setting and genre of a Vietnam War film allowed him to draw from inspiration ranging from the obvious Apocalypse Now to documentary footage of the true atrocities of the war. Tying this all together to make an entertaining film is an achievement and thanks in large part to the landmark performances of the cast.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">In The Beginning…</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/in-the-beginning" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="In The Beginning..." />
      <published>2020-06-12T00:00:00-05:00</published>
      <updated>2020-06-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/in-the-beginning</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/in-the-beginning">&lt;blockquote class=&quot;alignright&quot;&gt;“To be Black, to be Texan, I wouldn't trade for anything in the world. I thank God for both.&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the beginning&lt;/strong&gt; I wanted to write about Texas. I’ve always wanted to write about my home. Known throughout the world as the home of cowboys, 10 gallon hats and the Alamo, I know Texas to be much more: awe-inspiring landscapes; diverse and delicious foods: rich in culture and pride; and beautiful people from all walks of life. I set out to start a blog dedicated to illuminating all to the wider Texan experience, the Texas I know and love. As time went on, I found myself just as motivated to write about my other love: Melanin; Brothers and Sisters; my Niggas; African-Americans, Black People. To be Black, to be Texan, I wouldn’t trade for anything in the world. I thank God for both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not the first black man in Texas. Mustafa Azemmouri is widely considered to be the first person of African descent to step foot on this land but neither he nor I was the last. This land is home to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/beyonce/&quot;&gt;Queen Beys&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://history.house.gov/People/Detail/16031&quot;&gt;Congresswomen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biography.com/athlete/jack-johnson&quot;&gt;Heavyweight Champions&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://lemelson.mit.edu/resources/otis-boykin&quot;&gt;Inventors&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pbs.org/wgbh/americanexperience/features/flygirls-bessie-coleman/&quot;&gt;Pilots&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.independent.co.uk/news/obituaries/barry-white-36718.html&quot;&gt;Composers&lt;/a&gt; and innumerable more. Each one of these has their own story, their own struggles and triumphs, their own perspectives. It’s the goal of this site to share these stories, not just the ones from our rich and great history both those ones happening among us in the present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/logo/main-logo-brand.svg#left&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s what The Black Texan is: All things Black, All things Texan. It isn’t any one person or persons, it’s not just a specific place in or of the lone star state. The Black Texan is a site dedicated to sharing, chronicling, and uplifting, and the Black experience in Texas; all of it. From the Ensemble in Houston, to Dallas’ Smokey John’s, from Six Square in Austin to the people all over the state fighting against racism and working towards equality, The Black Texan will be there.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Jarrett Johnson</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="history" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">“To be Black, to be Texan, I wouldn't trade for anything in the world. I thank God for both.&quot;</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
