<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/author/jarrett/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2020-06-15T17:36:45-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/author/jarrett/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">The Black Texan | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>All things Black. All things Texan.</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Da 5 Bloods Review</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/Da-5-Bloods-Review" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Da 5 Bloods Review" />
      <published>2020-06-13T00:00:00-05:00</published>
      <updated>2020-06-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/Da-5-Bloods-Review</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Da-5-Bloods-Review">&lt;p&gt;The new Spike Lee feature &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflix.com/title/81045635&quot;&gt;Da 5 Bloods&lt;/a&gt; from Netflix is a movie unlike any other released so far this year. &lt;!--more--&gt; Many films strive to either be classified as “the’’ movie for the present moment and time (Lee’s last feature BlacKkKlansman for instance) and while it doesn’t seem like Lee directed the movie with regards either way, it would be hard not to appreciate the timeliness of this movie’s release and it’s subject matter. Da 5 Bloods tells the story of four Black Vietnam War Veterans traveling back to search for the remains of their fallen comrade and buried riches. They navigate the haunting legacy of their former leader Stormin Norman (played by Black Panther star Chadwick Boseman) which weaves through the past and present day, forcing Da Bloods to relive the horrors of war.  In part based on Wallace Terry’s collection of black soldiers’ accounts of the war, Da 5 Bloods is much more than a war movie. It’s mixing of genres and themes are handled masterfully by Lee who explores haunting memories of the past, the debt this country owes it’s black soldiers, and even what Black Americans owe each other. His expert direction is evident as well. The setting and genre of a Vietnam War film allowed him to draw from inspiration ranging from the obvious Apocalypse Now to documentary footage of the true atrocities of the war. Tying this all together to make an entertaining film is an achievement and thanks in large part to the landmark performances of the cast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2020/da-5-bloods-2.jpg#left&quot; alt=&quot;Delroy Lindo and Jonathon Majors from Da 5 Bloods&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The up and coming Dallas native Jonathan Majors shone brightly in films such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.metacritic.com/movie/hostiles&quot;&gt;Hostiles&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://a24films.com/films/the-last-black-man-in-san-francisco&quot;&gt;The Last Black Man in San Francisco&lt;/a&gt; and he continues this run of form with his performance as David, the son of one the titular Bloods. The youthfulness of this character plays as a contrast to the senior citizen rest of the main cast. Upon first seeing Da Bloods on screen their chemistry is palpable; it’s easy to believe these now aged men have been friends for decades. Isiah Whitlock Jr., Norm Lewis, Clarke Lewis, and Delroy Lindo are Da Bloods in present day, each processing the consequences of the war and their lives afterwards in their own way. While largely a fictional story, the film is rooted in the experience of black veterans. Abstract ideas from the role of Black Americans in the history of the American military, to the opioid crisis, to how best to respond to injustice and tragedy are illustrated through conversations between Da Bloods and various characters they encounter along the way. These conversations resemble the real ones being had by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gov.texas.gov/uploads/files/organization/twic/Veterans_in_Texas_2016_Update.pdf&quot;&gt;13% of Black Texans&lt;/a&gt;, though heighted by the situation Da Bloods find themselves in. Lee clearly has a lot to say on these things and doesn’t pull any punches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2020/da-5-bloods-3.jpg#wide&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These punches hit the hardest from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/name/nm0005148/&quot;&gt;Delroy Lindo’s&lt;/a&gt; character, Paul. It’s hard not to want to join in the online campaign already forming for a Lindo Oscar nomination. His is the Blood most plagued by the death of their former leader and the complicated relationship he has with his family drives some of the most emotional parts of the movie. A role that could have easily become a caricature was handled with nuance and passion. Ultimately, the same is true for the film at large. Da 5 Bloods is deservedly the best movie of the year so far and more than that, deserves a spot in the upper echelon of the Spike Lee.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Jarrett Johnson</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="review" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">The new Spike Lee feature Da 5 Bloods from Netflix is a movie unlike any other released so far this year. Many films strive to either be classified as “the’’ movie for the present moment and time (Lee’s last feature BlacKkKlansman for instance) and while it doesn’t seem like Lee directed the movie with regards either way, it would be hard not to appreciate the timeliness of this movie’s release and it’s subject matter. Da 5 Bloods tells the story of four Black Vietnam War Veterans traveling back to search for the remains of their fallen comrade and buried riches. They navigate the haunting legacy of their former leader Stormin Norman (played by Black Panther star Chadwick Boseman) which weaves through the past and present day, forcing Da Bloods to relive the horrors of war. In part based on Wallace Terry’s collection of black soldiers’ accounts of the war, Da 5 Bloods is much more than a war movie. It’s mixing of genres and themes are handled masterfully by Lee who explores haunting memories of the past, the debt this country owes it’s black soldiers, and even what Black Americans owe each other. His expert direction is evident as well. The setting and genre of a Vietnam War film allowed him to draw from inspiration ranging from the obvious Apocalypse Now to documentary footage of the true atrocities of the war. Tying this all together to make an entertaining film is an achievement and thanks in large part to the landmark performances of the cast.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">In The Beginning…</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/in-the-beginning" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="In The Beginning..." />
      <published>2020-06-12T00:00:00-05:00</published>
      <updated>2020-06-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/in-the-beginning</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/in-the-beginning">&lt;blockquote class=&quot;alignright&quot;&gt;“To be Black, to be Texan, I wouldn't trade for anything in the world. I thank God for both.&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the beginning&lt;/strong&gt; I wanted to write about Texas. I’ve always wanted to write about my home. Known throughout the world as the home of cowboys, 10 gallon hats and the Alamo, I know Texas to be much more: awe-inspiring landscapes; diverse and delicious foods: rich in culture and pride; and beautiful people from all walks of life. I set out to start a blog dedicated to illuminating all to the wider Texan experience, the Texas I know and love. As time went on, I found myself just as motivated to write about my other love: Melanin; Brothers and Sisters; my Niggas; African-Americans, Black People. To be Black, to be Texan, I wouldn’t trade for anything in the world. I thank God for both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not the first black man in Texas. Mustafa Azemmouri is widely considered to be the first person of African descent to step foot on this land but neither he nor I was the last. This land is home to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/beyonce/&quot;&gt;Queen Beys&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://history.house.gov/People/Detail/16031&quot;&gt;Congresswomen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biography.com/athlete/jack-johnson&quot;&gt;Heavyweight Champions&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://lemelson.mit.edu/resources/otis-boykin&quot;&gt;Inventors&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pbs.org/wgbh/americanexperience/features/flygirls-bessie-coleman/&quot;&gt;Pilots&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.independent.co.uk/news/obituaries/barry-white-36718.html&quot;&gt;Composers&lt;/a&gt; and innumerable more. Each one of these has their own story, their own struggles and triumphs, their own perspectives. It’s the goal of this site to share these stories, not just the ones from our rich and great history both those ones happening among us in the present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/logo/main-logo-brand.svg#left&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s what The Black Texan is: All things Black, All things Texan. It isn’t any one person or persons, it’s not just a specific place in or of the lone star state. The Black Texan is a site dedicated to sharing, chronicling, and uplifting, and the Black experience in Texas; all of it. From the Ensemble in Houston, to Dallas’ Smokey John’s, from Six Square in Austin to the people all over the state fighting against racism and working towards equality, The Black Texan will be there.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Jarrett Johnson</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="history" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">“To be Black, to be Texan, I wouldn't trade for anything in the world. I thank God for both.&quot;</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
